<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Satyam&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Satyam&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change</title>
      <link>/blogs/climate1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/climate1/</guid>
      <description>This analysis focuses on Climate change as measured by temperature anomalies in given years. If there is an increasing amount of anomalies in average temperatures measured through time this will indicate that average temperatures are changing. With the analysis done below, the conclusion is very straightfroward in proving that temperatures are rising increasingky quickly and that most of the anomalies are measured during the winter months. Further study through a density plot measure confirms this conclusion as the current decade has experienced the highest delta regarding temperature anomalies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID_19</title>
      <link>/blogs/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/covid/</guid>
      <description>Taking into account the current pandemic and historic moment Earth is going through at the moment, not talking about COVID-19 would be an absurdity. With the below analysis, the goal is to understand which tranches of the population are most imapcted by the pandemic in terms of mortality. The focus here is on age and sex, analyzed in comparison to co-morbidities and admissions into ICU.
The results are stunning. Around 50% of women between 60 and 69 and men between 50 and 59 who were admitted into ICU perished from COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDP</title>
      <link>/blogs/gdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/gdp/</guid>
      <description>The intention of the below code is to measure how components of GDP have evolved over the last 4 decades for 3 countries. To accomplish this the data will be measured in both absolute and relative terms. STudyingt he various components is useful in understanding what drives wealth in a given country.
For this study, France, India and SIngapore were chosen due to their very different economic models and also in part due to the authors personal preference after having lvied in all 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media and Email Usage</title>
      <link>/blogs/gss1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/gss1/</guid>
      <description>The most commonly used communication medium today remains emails, but social media is representing an ever greater share of communication methods. It is also a big time consumer as can be seen with the analysis below. Using R and statistics, the analysis seperates into tranches on Gender and Education the average usage of social media and then takes a global overview of how much time people in the population studied spend checking their emails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trump&#39;s Approval Ratings</title>
      <link>/blogs/trump/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/trump/</guid>
      <description>Probably the most controversial president at the moment, Trump divides opinions more than any other political leader of recent times. Interestingly, and to everyone’s disbelief, even when polls forecasted him to lose against Hillary CLinton, he surprised everyone by being elected to office.
Anyhow, by continuously measuring polls throughout his tenure we see the following - that while Trump’s net approval (approval - disapproval) ratings have remained negative, they were far worst in the first year of his presidency, rose slightly in the second year to -10% and then evolved around there, until recently rising again slightly -7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worldwide Population Statistics</title>
      <link>/blogs/pop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/pop/</guid>
      <description>On this page, the intention is show off the power of R Studio in coming up with easy to understand statistics covering large amounts of data. As such, focusing on variables of HIV, fertility, GDP per capita, Mortality and school enrollment, the code below shows the relationship between them.
Starting with the relationship between HIV prevalence and Life Expectancy, the analysis concludes that there is a negative correlation which is most visible in Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yield Curve</title>
      <link>/blogs/yield1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/yield1/</guid>
      <description>With the below the objective is to understand how yield curve inversions, that is when the rate of long dated US Treasury (say 10 years maturity) dips below that of a short dated UST (say the 3month maturity), can serve as a predictor of recessions. Traditionally yields of longer dated securities should be higher than those of shorter maturity securities due to the longer risk exposure. Its is commonly believed today that when the relationship between short and long is inverted this translates into an impeding recession in the coming months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/blogs/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Everything or Nothing, an Auto-Biography of an Ambitious Globe Trotter Two fun facts about me before I get on with my autobiography; I am a black belt in Karate and have a French-Indian background. This means I am as comfortable around:
 Bordeaux wine and cheese, Dhal Bhat and Curry, Dim sums and a warm broth of Udon  My early years as a globe trotter I was born on 7th July 1997 in Paris to an Indian mother and French father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
